对于你的指控
I've never confessed to the crime
我从不认罪
you want me to be guilty of.
我历尽千辛万苦
I've come halfway round the world
就是为了确保你不能活着离开监牢
to make sure you never get out of here alive.
默多克・福伊尔 你认识他吗 长官?
Murdoch Foyle. You know him,sir?
费雪小姐认为是默多克・福伊尔谋杀了她妹妹
Miss Fisher believes Murdoch Foyle murdered her sister.
"我知道你已经采取行动"
'I realise you have taken steps
"来确保我永无止尽地待在监狱里"
to ensure I remain at His Majesty's pleasure indefinitely.
"而我写信来就是希望你能同我见面"
But I write in the hope that you will agree to meet with me.
"你想要真相 而我想要自由"
You want the truth above all else,and I want my freedom.
尊敬的默多克・福伊尔
Yours Murdoch Foyle
福尔死了
Foyle's dead.
他逃狱成功的前提是没人认领尸体
The plan he cooked up relied on the bodies not being claimed.
但他母亲一接到死讯 就要求火葬尸体
But when his mother got the news,she asked for him to be cremated.
他可能被活活烧死了
He would have been burned alive.
- 怎么了? - 这是詹妮的
- What is it? - It was Janey's.
她失踪那天头上就系的这丝带
She was wearing ribbons in her hair the day she disappeared.
我不明白 肯定是他来了
I don't understand. It must be him.
- 我也希望这是个巧合 - 本来就是
- I've tried to dismiss it as coincidence. - That's all it is.
默多克・福伊尔在狱中死了
Murdoch Foyle died in prison.
但万一他骗了我们所有人呢?
But what if he's duped us all?
他用诡计 或者买通别人捏造死讯
With trickery,or he paid people to help feign his death
好让我们以为他死掉了
so that we all think he's gone,
而实际上他在伺机报复
but he's just biding his time waiting to strike.
福尔已经死了 芙莱妮
Foyle's dead,Phryne.
麻烦你们载我一程好么
I wonder if I could trouble you for a lift.
我要去圣基尔达 但我的车子坏了
My car won't start and I need to get back to St. Kilda.
不好意思 打扰了
Excuse me,I'm so sorry to bother you.
我可以借用一下你家的电话吗?
Do you think I could use your telephone?
你是...
You are...
- 简 他在哪? - 默多克・福伊尔在哪
Jane! Where is he? Where's Murdoch Foyle?
他会回来的
He'll be back.
曼塞斯法老的诅咒
费雪小姐探案集
你给我再复述一遍
I need you to go over this one more time.
把福尔的每句话都告诉我
Tell me every word Foyle said to you.
我昨晚已经全告诉罗宾逊探长了
I told Inspector Robinson everything last night.
不好意思 打扰了
I'm sorry to bother you.
我好像把我的家门钥匙落在车里了
I appear to have left my house keys in my car.
他问我借电话
He asked to use the telephone.
我给他倒了杯茶 他跟我聊了会历史
I offered him a cup of tea and he just talked about history.
- 我是个大学教授 - 真的吗?
- I was a professor at the university. - Really?
我热衷于古代世界
Ancient worlds are my passion.
我进来的时候就觉得不对劲
I knew something was wrong when I came in.
不是你的错 巴特勒先生
It's not your fault,Mr Butler.
- 他一定很有魅力 - 是的
- I'm sure he was charming. - He was.
你根本不知道这人会做出什么! 简
You have no idea what this man is capable of,Jane!
我知道他伤害了你妹妹
I know he did something to your sister.
如果他越狱了 事情会很严重
And if he escaped from prison,it must've been serious.
- 查出什么了吗? - 没有
- Did you find anything? - Nothing.
我们盘查了昨晚他下车附近的两个街区
Door-knocked for two blocks where we dropped him off last night.
- 没人听说过他 - 说明他还流落在外
- No-one's heard of him. - So he could be anywhere.
我在车后座发现了这个
I found this in the back of the cab.
也许是他昨晚掉的
Maybe he dropped it last night.
艾伯特古董古玩店
Albert's Antiques and Curiosities.
阿伯茨福德市 萨默斯街 18号
18 Somers Street,Abbotsford.
- 费雪小姐? - 怎么了?
- Miss Fisher? - What is it?
福尔入狱前开了一家古董店
Foyle had an antique shop before he went to prison.
店名不同 但地址一样
It's a different name,same address.
- 那我们去开车 - 不用
- Right,let's take the cab. - No.
- 你和赛斯待在这 - 这可能是个圈套
- You and Cec stay here. - But it could be a trap.
如果这家伙真有你说的那么危险...
If this bloke's as dangerous as you say...
他确实有! 所以我要你留下来陪简
He is! That's why I want you to stay with Jane.
- 我要和您一起去 - 不 桃乐西
- But I'm coming with you. - No,Dot.
万一的确是圈套呢? 您不能一个人去
What if Bert's right? You can't go alone.
那就走吧
Come on then.
伯特 打电话给罗宾逊探长
Telephone Inspector Robinson,please,Bert.
让他在那儿跟我们碰面
Ask him to meet us there.
已经九点了 应该八点就开门了啊
It's nearly nine. It says he opens at eight.
我们要敲门吗?
Should we knock?
嘘! 我听到了点动静
Sh! I can hear something.
可怜的小东西被锁在里面了啊
Poor thing's locked in.
他叼着什么?
What's he got?
那是根手指 桃乐西
That's a finger,Dot.
给 拿着这个
Here,hold this.
跟在后面 桃乐西
Stay back,Dot.
圣母玛利亚!
Holy Mary,Mother of God!
你觉得这是福尔干的?
So you think this is Foyle's doing?
一定是
It has to be.
这儿以前是他的店
This used to be his shop,
且艾伯特・蒙克顿是他庭审时的品德荣誉证人
and Albert Monkton was a character witness at his trial.
为被告方作证么?
For the defence?
真不知道他当时怎么想的
I hate to think what he has in mind for the prosecution.
福尔来这里是有原因的
Foyle came here for a reason.
为了报复 或者找什么东西
For revenge,or to find something.
我更担心的是福尔会再去你家
I'm more worried about Foyle paying you another visit.
赛斯和伯特在那他不敢再来的
He won't try that again. Not with Cec and Bert there.
店已经封锁了 长官
The shop has been secured,sir,
殡仪人员想进来收尸
and the undertakers would like to come in and collect the body.
除了出血的鼻子 无明显死因
No obvious cause of death,aside from a bloodied nose.
让他们进来 看看验尸官怎么说
Call them in,and see what the Coroner has to say.
是 长官
Yes,sir.
那个被打碎的柜子怎么办呢?
What about the cabinet that was broken into?
- 我得四处看看 - 不 你别看了
- I need to look around. - No,you don't.
- 不 我要看 - 不 你不要!
- Yes,I do. - No,you don't.
此案你干涉的太多了
You're too involved with this case.
你得回家睡一觉
You need to go home and get some sleep.
带她回去 威廉姆斯小姐
Make sure she does,Miss Williams.
快走吧 小姐
Come on,Miss.
噢 这太荒唐了! 如果再让我看一眼
Oh,this is ridiculous! If I could have another look around.
- 等会吧 小姐 - 那是什么?
- Later,Miss. - What's that?
这是默多克・福伊尔
It's Murdoch Foyle.
休! 杰克还在这吗?
Hugh! Is Jack still here?
恩... 探长刚回局里
Um... the Inspector's just headed back to the station.
- 你要找他吗? - 不用
- Do you need him? - No.
暂且不用
Not immediately.
那... 我锁门了
I'll... just lock up then.
关于受害人鼻孔附近的伤
Did the cuts around the victim's nostrils
你有什么想法吗 警探 ?
remind you of anything,Constable?
恩..让我想起了上周在诺斯寇特发现的尸体
Um... the body that was found in Northcote last week,sir.
验尸官认为他是吸毒过量 对吧?
The Coroner thought he was on dope,didn't he?
如果我没记错的话 是可卡因
Cocaine,if I recall.
可除了他鼻子上的伤
The Coroner couldn't find any evidence of intoxication,
验尸官没找到任何中毒的迹象 这儿
apart from the damage to his nose. Here.
"两个鼻孔内均有损伤"
"Abrasions to the inside of both nostrils."
费雪小姐坚持认为这是默多克・福伊尔干的
Miss Fisher's convinced Murdoch Foyle's responsible.
你怎么看呢 长官
What do you think,sir?
我们还是像往常一样过一遍所有证据为好
I think We go through the evidence like we do with any case.
当然 长官
Of course,sir.
打电话到验尸所
Telephone the Coroner's office
问他们我能不能看一下蒙克顿的尸体
to see if we can view Monkton's body.
还有诺斯寇特谋杀案的受害人尸体
And I want to see the Northcote murder victim as well.
如果费雪小姐打电话过来
If Miss Fisher telephones,
- 帮我接进来 - 好的 长官
- put her through to me. - Yes,sir.
送牛奶!
Milko!
中间这个是福尔
Foyle's the one in the middle.
左边这个年轻人是艾伯特 蒙克顿
This young man on the left is Albert Monkton,
今早发现的受害人
the victim we found this morning.
看起来像不像金字塔 赛斯?
Looks like the Pyramids,eh,Cec?
我们骑马的地方
Where we camped the horses.
是的 沙漠里的吉萨金字塔 踢足球的好地方
Yeah,Giza,in the desert. Great place to kick a footy.
也可以进行考古挖掘
Or set up an archaeological dig.
其它几个人是谁?
Who are the others?
他们都比福尔年轻 应该是学生吧
They're all younger than Foyle. Perhaps students.
他战前曾在古代历史系教课
He lectured in the Department of Antiquities before the war.
所以你觉得这是福尔那家伙故意流下来的?
So you reckon this Foyle joker left it on purpose?
伯特 他是在挑衅"有本事就抓住我啊"
He's baiting me,Burt. Catch me if you can.
他把那张名片留在你车后座也是这个目的
Same reason he left that card in the back of your cab.
桃乐西 我要你再回一趟古董店
Dot,and you should go back to the shop,
清点一遍那个被打碎的柜子里所有东西
and do an inventory of everything in the cabinet that was ransacked.
没准能帮我们搞清福尔到底在找些什么
It may throw up some clues as to what Foyle was after.
- 好的 - 你们谁跟着她去吧 - 好的
Of course. And one of you go with her. - Righto.
虽然福尔不会傻到重回哪里
Foyle wouldn't be foolish enough to return there,
但我不想让桃乐西单独行动
but I don't want Dot left alone.
另外... 你们可能要硬闯进去
Besides... you may need to break in.
我不知道你是怎么
I don't know how you managed
再次绕开前台直接闯进的 费雪小姐
to bypass the reception desk again,Miss Fisher,
但我很乐意叫人强行带你离开
but I am quite happy to have you forcibly removed.
你要叫谁? 警察吗?
Who will you call? The police?
- 啊 看谁来了 - 费雪小姐
- Ah,look who's here. - Miss Fisher.
你好 杰克 我已经尽力小憩了
Hello,Jack. I tried to take a nap
但我心如野马不可控制
but wild horses couldn't make me.
我已经跟费雪小姐说过她无权进入这里
And I've explained to Miss Fisher that she has no right to be here.
既然这样 我就当费雪小姐是荣誉警探吧
In that case,I deem Miss Fisher my honorary constable.
我已经仔细检查了鼻孔处的伤口
I've taken a closer look at the cuts around the nostrils.
好像是由某种器具造成的
They seem to have been made by some kind of an instrument.
什么器具?
What kind of instrument?
我可以说话吗? - 不
May I say something? - No.
目前还很难判断
It's hard to say at this stage,
但一定不是寻常的刀具
but it wasn't a conventional knife.
- 我无意中发现了一些新证据 - 哪来的
- But I came across some new evidence. - How?
你离开之后我在侧门上发现的
After you left. It was stuck in the side door.
据麦克医生所说 这是一把埃及...
According to Dr Mac,it's an Egyptian...
这是个防腐工具 用来移除重要器官的
It's an embalming tool,for removing vital organs.
比如说大脑
Like the brain.
我们一般不检查大脑 除非有什么特殊理由
Well,we don't examine the brain unless we have good reason.
检查一下大脑是不是没了 这理由不错吧?
How about to check if it's missing?
请撬开艾伯特 蒙克顿的脑壳 强森先生
Crack open Albert Monkton's skull,please,Mr Johnson.
我们等着
We'll wait.
有东西不见了
Something's missing.
"曼塞斯国王统治时期的银色马镫环"
"Silver stirrup Ring,in the reign of King Memses"
"公元前2600年 第五世王朝"
"Dynasty Five,2600 BC."
- 没东西了 - 给我看
- Nothing. - Show me.
有张纸条
There's a note.
"我亲爱的维拉 我和弟兄们"
"My darling Vera,me and the blokes found this treasure"
"在君王谷发现了这个珍宝"
"in a tomb near the Valley of the Kings."
"它像你一样珍贵而美丽"
"It's precious and beautiful like you are."
"好好保存它 我很快就会回家见你"
"Keep it safe and I'll come home to you soon."
"爱你的 塞德里克"
All my love,your Cedric.'
1915年 一定是个挖掘者
1915. Must've been a digger.
还有一些残余
There were some remnants,
但大脑的大部分构造被熟练地移走了
but most of the brain has been expertly removed.
你是对的 费雪小姐
You were right,Miss Fisher.
问题是为什么要这样?
The question is why?
我确实在鼻腔内发现了些东西
I did discover something inside the nasal cavity,
你可以拿来作证据
and you'll want this as evidence.
- 一块石头? - 恩
- A stone? - Hm.
是象形文字?
Hieroglyphics?
那个诺斯寇特的受害人呢?
What about the Northcote victim?
可以推断他也受了同样的摧残么?
Can we assume he suffered the same procedure?
各种迹象确实证明了这一点
All the signs point that way.
比如两个人鼻孔周围有相同的伤口
Same cuts around the nostrils.
都被用某种麻醉药物
Both had been heavily sedated
深度麻醉
with some sort of paralysis drug.
最惨无人道的是
The nasty thing is,
整个取脑过程中两人都是完全清醒的
they were completely conscious during the procedure.
出来吧
Come on.
看
Yes.
一样的石头
Same calling card.
这男人是谁? 我好像见过他
Who is this man? I've seen him before.
第一个受害人叫詹姆斯・沃特斯
The first victim's name was James Waters.
他曾是登记处的职员
He was an employee in the Registry office.
从一个小杂工一直做到了高级文员
Worked his way up from office boy to senior clerk
记录人的孵化 配对和派遣
with Hatch,Match and Dispatch.
就是出生 婚姻 和死亡
Births,marriages and deaths.
他一定从某种方式上和福尔有牵扯
Somehow he got in contact with Foyle.
看这里 毕业于墨尔本大学
Here it is. Educated Melbourne University.
我猜他主修是古代史
My guess is Ancient History.
我们中的一个得去一趟古代史系
One of us needs to pay a visit to the Antiquities Department,
福尔曾在那任教
where Foyle used to lecture.
看看你能不能把这些破解了
See if you can have these translated.
希尔小姐的档案 长官
The file on Miss Hill,sir.
蜜儿特・希尔
Myrtle Hill.
她就是那个逃脱了他魔掌的幸运儿
She was the lucky girl who escaped his clutches.
我想再看一下这个案子
I'm going back through the case.
看有没有指向福尔的遗漏线索
See if anything points to where Foyle might be lying low.
希尔小姐
Miss Hill.
福特斯普的警察说你们要找我
Footscray coppers said you wanted to see me.
要是关于租房子的事 他想都别想
If it's about the rent,he can wait till hell freezes over,
因为那个地方不可能养猪
because that place was not fit for pigs.
不 是关于另一件事
No,it's about another matter.
我们想问您一些问题
We need to ask you some questions.
关于什么?
What about?
那个绑架你未遂的男人 默多克・福伊尔
Murdoch Foyle,the man who tried to abduct you.
事情过去很久了 我记不清了
It was a long time ago. I can't remember.
嗯... 希尔小姐 默多克・福伊尔越狱了
Um... Miss Hill,Murdoch Foyle's escaped from prison,
抓住他需要你的帮忙
and we need your help to find him.
我可不能多嘴 他要是回来报复我怎么办?
I'm the one who blabbed. What if he comes after me?
那天放学后我在等电车
I was waiting at the tram stop after school,
他想用嘉年华的门票引诱我
and he tried to sweet-talk me with tickets to the carnival.
拜托了 我不想浪费这两张票
Please,I'd hate them to go to waste.
我本想带着我女儿去 但她...
I was meant to take my little girl,but she...
- 她前不久去世了 - 怎么了?
- she passed away recently. - How?
她得了猩红热
Scarlet fever.
嘉年华的票准备送她的生日礼物
Carnival was supposed to be her birthday treat.
我的生日也快到了
It's my birthday soon too.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
所以我邀请他和我同去
So I said he should come too.
我们把票都花在旋转木马上了
We used up all the tickets on the carousel.
那时已经很晚了
It was late by then.
他说他有家古玩店
He said he had a shop where he sold treasures,
就在那附近
not far away,
我们可以一起去他那 然后他骑摩托送我回家
and if we went there he could drive me home in his motor car.
但到了那 他突然说他口渴
But when we got there he said he was thirsty.
他要我请喝点
He wanted me to try
他自己做的独特的姜汁酒
some of his special ginger wine he'd made himself.
福尔先生说没有关系
Mr Foyle said that it would be OK
因为我是被选中的女孩们之一
because I was one of the chosen ones.
他有一对高脚杯 很古老的
He had goblets. Old one.
档案上说你被下药了 是的
The file says you were drugged. That's right.
我想离开
I wanted to leave.
然后他就抓住了我
That's when he grabbed me,
想要把剩下的酒灌进我嘴里
and poured the rest of the drink down my throat.
你说 你醒来的时候已经在教堂里了?
And you woke up in the church,you said?
是的 我不记得是哪儿了
That's right. I don't remember where.
但是我还记得那个救了我的女士
But I do remember the lady who rescued me.
她... 她有一头乌黑的卷发
She... she had dark wavy hair.
如果你再见到她能认出来么?
Would you recognise her if you met her again?
我记得她的样子
I could have imagined her.
她就像一个天使
Maybe she was more like an angel.
是来救我的
She'd come to save me.
进来
Enter.
- 下午好 - 呃 桌子那儿没有接待的人
- Good afternoon. - The... desk was unattended.
是啊 学校放假了嘛
Yes,academic holidays.
却是我搞研究的好时候 我能为你效劳吗?
But a good time for my research. How can I help?
我是芙莱妮・费雪 私家侦探
Miss Phryne Fisher,private detective.
我能为女神探您做点什么?
What can I do for a lady detective?
我希望您帮我翻译点东西
I was hoping you could help with some translations.
一种象形文字
From hieroglyphics.
这看起来像德本  埃及新王国时期的计量品
These look like debens. A unit of weight from the New Kingdom.
是早期的货币形式
An early form of currency.
- 我能拿出来看看吗? - 当然可以
- May I take them out? - Of course.
是的 好像是一种古怪的象形文字组合
Yes,seems to be a curious mix of hieroglyphics,
是僧侣文字和之后通俗文字的结合
Hieratic script and the later demotic version,
通俗文字就是指"普通老百姓写的字"
demotic being 'the people's writing'.
嗯 如果你把这些留下来
Well,if you leave them with me,
我可以更精确地估算它们的年代
I can date them properly and narrow it down.
我猜你认识一个叫默多克・福伊尔的人
I believe you know a man called Murdoch Foyle.
是的 我读书时他曾在这里讲课
Yes,he used to lecture here in my student days,
但我很多年没有他的消息了
but I haven't seen anything of him for years.
他前不久越狱了...
He's recently escaped from jail...
..警察正在通缉他
..and the police are hunting him down.
上帝啊
Good Lord.
那是1913年欧洲的春季
It was the European spring of 1913.
福尔对古代世界一直很神往
Foyle was so passionate about the ancient world,
那是我们第一次去法老之乡埃及
and it was our first trip to the Land of the Pharaohs.
左边的那个是艾伯特 蒙克顿
That's Albert Monkton on the left,
那个是年轻的詹姆斯・沃特斯
and that's the young James Waters .
都是你同学?
Fellow students?
我们那时关系不错
We were very close back then.
去吉萨金字塔时都激动不已
Terribly excited about visiting Giza,
在帝王谷我们尝试了第一次挖掘
and attempting our first dig in the Valley of the Kings.
我已经很多年没见过詹姆斯了
But I haven't seen James for years,
但我和艾伯特还时不时联系一下
though I keep in spasmodic touch with Albert.
- 没别的了吗 - 嗯?
- Not anymore.- Hm?
艾伯特 蒙克顿今天凌晨被谋杀了
Albert Monkton was murdered in the early hours of this morning.
詹姆斯・沃尔特上周被杀害了
James Walters was killed last week,
默多克・福伊尔是头号嫌犯
and Murdoch Foyle is the prime suspect.
- 天呐 - 我估计你现在也十分危险了
- My God. - I can only assume you're in danger too.
站在福尔身边的这个女人是谁?
What about this woman standing beside Foyle?
她也是一个学生
Her,yes,a fellow student,
她叫特里萨・卡瓦莉
Teresa Cavalli.
一个年轻女孩
It's unusual for a young lady
和几个男性一同出行不太寻常啊
to travel with a group of men like that.
她是默多克的最爱
She was Murdoch's favourite,
那时是很... 不合适的
in more ways than were... appropriate
特别是对一个严谨的天主教女孩来说
for a strict Catholic girl back then.
我也要提醒她 你知道哪能找到她吗?
I need to warn her too. Do you know where I can find her?
对不起 一战后我就没见过她了
I'm sorry. I haven't seen her since the war.
如果蜜儿特被下药了
If Myrtle was drugged,
有可能整件事都是她想象出来的
she could have imagined the whole thing.
我们给她看了所有嫌犯的照片
We took her through all our criminal photographs.
但她认不出任何人
But she didn't recognise anyone.
她唯一记得的就是一头黑色长发
All she remembers is long,dark hair.
黑色卷发? 是的
Dark,wavy hair? Hm.
特里萨・卡瓦莉
Teresa Cavalli.
罗德说她是福尔的情人
Rhodes identified her as Foyle's lover.
- 她可能是同谋 - 或者曾试图要阻止他
- She could've been his accomplice. - Or tried to stop him.
我们把蜜儿特找来让她看看照片
Let's get Myrtle back in and show her this photograph.
我们警局见吧
I'll meet you at the station.
偷来的
Stolen goods.
- 这是什么? - 从打碎的橱柜里找到的
- What is it? - It's from the smashed cabinet.
按标签来看 原本应该装着一枚银戒指
According to the ticket,it's meant to hold a silver ring,
但是没了
but it's missing.
会是福尔打碎后拿走的吗
Could be what this Foyle bloke was after.
你们俩干得不错
Well done,both of you.
就是她 救我的那个女士
That's her,the woman who saved me.
那个教堂你还记得什么吗?
What can you tell me about the church where she left you?
这是费雪小姐
This is Miss Fisher.
她正在协助我们调查此案
She's helping us with her investigation.
默多克・福伊尔也诱拐了我妹妹
Murdoch Foyle abducted my sister as well.
就在你逃走的两周后 希尔小姐
Two weeks after you escaped him,Miss Hill.
她逃掉了吗?
Did she escape?
没有
I'm afraid not.
噢 我很抱歉 我...我希望还能帮上忙
Oh,I'm so sorry. I... I wish I could help more.
我希望能记起来更多事
I wish I could remember more.
因为你默多克・福伊尔才能被绳之以法
You're the reason Murdoch Foyle's been locked up all this time.
你已经够勇敢了
You've been brave enough.
谢谢你 蜜儿特
Thank you,Myrtle.
我已经吓坏了 说实话
I'm scared witless,w to tell you the truth,
既然他又逃出来了
now that he's out there again.
也许我得躲去我悉尼的奶奶那儿
Maybe I should go to my nan's in Sydney.
我希望你们尽快抓到他
I hope you nab him.
我来付她的车费
I'll pay her train fare.
如果方便请把她安排在头等舱
First class,if you can put her on it.
当然
Of course.
特里萨・卡瓦莉 意大利人
Teresa Cavalli. Italian.
我猜她是个天主教徒
I assume she was Catholic.
推测正确
Correct deduction.
我猜你会很高兴知道她住的教堂
You might also like to know the church she was left in
离里士满警局没有几步路
was walking distance from Richmond Police Station.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的 科林斯
Good. Now,Collins.
你给我多找点包肉纸来
I need you to find me a ream of butcher's paper.
这是离里士满警局最近的天主教堂了
It's the closest Catholic church to Richmond Police Station.
悲伤女士教区 这名挺吸引人的
Our Lady of Sorrows. Bet that draws a crowd.
奥列瑞神父一定在听忏悔 我们得等一等
Father O'Leary must be hearing confessions. We'll have to wait.
没时间等了 奥列瑞神父 有急事找你!
We can't. father O'Leary! It's an emergency!
你想做个紧急的忏悔吗?
It is an urgent confession you're after?
不 谢谢 我的罪恶太多了不提也罢
No,thank you. My sins are too many and varied to mention,
老实说 我还打算继续罪恶下去
and frankly,I intend to continue sinning,
我就直说吧 我是来找特里萨・卡瓦莉的
so I won't waste your time. I'm looking for Teresa Cavalli.
我上次见你时你还是个小不点
I haven't seen you since you were a mere slip of a thing,
是在圣茱德奉献游行的时候
in the Offertory Procession at St Jude's.
神父 这位是我的雇主费雪小姐
Miss Fisher is my employer,Father,
她想请你帮个忙
and she needs your help.
她是个新教徒 但这不是主要问题
She is a Protestant,but that's not the only problem.
我是来找特里萨・卡瓦莉的
I'm looking for Teresa Cavalli.
她现在命悬一线了
Her life hangs in the balance.
一位先生昨晚也打电话找她了
A gentleman phoned the presbytery last night also looking for her.
他是谁?
Who was he?
他自称是他哥哥
He claimed to be her brother,
但我知道卡瓦莉家只有女儿
but I know the Cavallis only have daughters.
我告诉他我不知道她去哪儿了
I told him I'd no idea where she was.
我相信上帝会宽恕这个谎言的
I think it's a lie the Lord will forgive.
那她究竟在哪里?
So where is she then?
她已经是个修女了
She's a fully-fledged Sister of Mercy,
她现在叫柏妮思修女
by the name of Sister Bernice.
她加入了修道院? 回车上吧 桃乐西
She joined the nunnery? Back in the car,Dot.
- 神父 我们去哪找她? - 不必着急
- How can we find her,Father? - Oh,you'll have the devil of a time.
她就在对面的修道院
She's in the convent just across the way.
- 谢谢你 神父 - 上帝保佑你 桃乐西
- Thank you,Father. - Bless you,Dorothy.
你是特里萨・卡瓦莉?
Teresa Cavalli?
- 是 我曾经是 - 我是芙莱妮・费雪
- Yes,I was once. - I'm Phryne Fisher.
我有些事想要问你
I need to ask you some questions
关于你以前的老师默多克・福伊尔的
about your former teacher Murdoch Foyle.
我认为是他绑架并杀害了我妹妹
I believe he abducted and murdered my sister,
而他最近越狱了
and he has recently escaped from jail.
我十五年前加入了教会
I joined the order 15 years ago,
那时起我和默多克・福伊尔就没有任何瓜葛了
and I've had nothing to do with Murdoch Foyle in all that time.
我知道他曾是你的爱人 你肯定能提供些线索
But I know he was your lover. Surely you have some insight.
我能帮忙做什么 长官?
Anything I can help with,sir?
福尔告诉蜜儿特她是被选中的女孩们
Foyle told Myrtle she was one of the 'chosen ones'.
为什么被选中 长官?
Why chosen,sir?
问得好 科林斯
Good question,Collins.
"被选中的女孩们" 复数 应该还有其他人
'Chosen ones',plural,suggests there were others,
即使他每次只绑架一个
even though he was only tried for one kidnapping.
詹妮在弗莱明顿被拐走
Janey was taken from Flemington,
蜜儿特在卡尔顿
Myrtle from Carlton,
两个地点离他工作的大学都非常近
both close to the university where he worked.
我想知道是否还有别的女孩也在同区域被拐走
I want to know if any other girls were taken from the same area.
我们要找周围多远的区域呢 长官?
And how wide should we be looking,sir?
我要距离大学半径四公里范围内
I want the files from any unsolved disappearance
所有未侦破的失踪案件资料
within a four-mile radius of the university
- 从福尔入狱前三年开始找起 - 是长官
- for the three years before Foyle went to jail. - Yes,sir.
我们所有人都被他控制着 这是真的
All of us were in his thrall,it's true,
直到那趟帝王谷之旅 事情才有所变化
until things soured after that trip to the Valley of the Kings
我们在那儿发现了曼塞斯国王的陵墓
where we discovered King Memses' tomb,
里面满是珍宝
full of treasures.
我们重新封了那个墓
We resealed the grave,
默多克要我们发誓保守秘密直到有机会再去
and Murdoch swore us to secrecy until we could return.
但他入狱了 后来一战爆发了
But he went to jail,then the war intervened.
蜜儿特・希尔的口供里提到了一对黄金高脚杯
Myrtle Hill's evidence mentioned a pair of gold goblets.
那是我们带出来的唯一物品
That was all we took.
默多克想用它来证明我们的发现
Murdoch wanted something to prove our discovery.
但是不久后他就被学校解雇了
But he was dismissed from the university soon afterwards,
后来盘了个古董店
and bought the antique store.
- 他为什么被解雇 - 他变得暴躁而疯狂
- Why was he dismissed? - He became angry and fanatical.
他觉得由他发现曼塞斯的陵墓是天意
He thought it was fitting that he discovered Memses' tomb
因为他们都出生于冬季的第二十一天
because they were both born on the 21st day of Proyet,
就是尼罗河退潮的时候
when the Nile recedes.
事实上 我们都对发现古墓是命中注定的
In fact,we were all entranced with the notion
这个说法感到欣喜痴迷
that our discovery was predestined.
那出了什么问题?
So what went wrong?
默多克开始痴迷于
Murdoch became obsessed
他是曼塞斯的尘世转生生这个想法
with the notion that he was Memses' earthly reincarnation,
而像曼塞斯一样 他需要四个女神陪伴他
and like him,he needed the four goddesses to accompany him
到达他阴间的王国
to his kingdom in the underworld.
我原以为这只是他的美好幻想 知道...
I thought it was just a romantic notion until...
蜜儿特・希尔
Myrtle Hill.
我想跟他言归于好 所以我去了他的店
I wanted to patch things up between us so I went to his shop.
但门是锁着的
But the door was locked.
她看上去大概八岁
She looked about eight.
看起来很开心 毫无戒备之心
She seemed happy enough,trusting.
直到...
Until...
嘘!
Shh!
我找了个机会 趁他回去之前把她救出去了
I took a chance. I got her out of there before he came back.
她晕晕乎乎的
She was woozy.
是被下了药
Drugged.
我把她留在"悲伤女士教堂"希望她平安无恙
I left her at Our Lady of Sorrows,hoping she was safe.
但这一切让我的良心深受谴责
But it weighed heavily on my conscience.
所以 是你给警察送了那封匿名信
So it was you who sent that anonymous letter to the police.
但还是没来得及救你的妹妹
Too late for your sister.
我能做的只是不停地祈求原谅
All I can do is keep praying for forgiveness.
你知道福尔已经杀了
Did you know Foyle killed
詹姆斯・沃特斯和艾伯特・蒙克顿吗?
James Waters and Albert Monkton?
福尔正在找你 你得离开这里
Foyle is looking for you. You need to get away from here.
我明天一早就走
I'll leave first thing in the morning.
他在古董店里找某样东西
He was looking for something in the antique shop.
- 他偷了一个马蹄型的银戒指 - 不是他
- He stole a silver stirrup ring. - No,he didn't.
是我先偷走的
I stole it first.
- 埃塞尔・古德温 年龄? - 十二岁
- Ethel Goodwin,age? - 12 years of age.
于1914年五月十二日在弗莱明顿
Disappeared from outside a grocer's store
一家杂货店门口失踪
in Flemington,12 May 1914.
她去那里为她母亲买头痛散
She went to buy headache powders for her mother.
琼・罗森 九岁于1913年八月十三日失踪
Joan Rosen,aged nine,disappeared 13 August,1913.
艾伯特告诉我
Albert told me
一位战后遗孀带来这枚曼塞斯法老的戒指
a war widow had brought in King Memses's ring,
而他找到一家英国博物馆 愿意出高价购买
and he'd found a British museum willing to pay a fortune for it.
不知怎么的 默多克在狱中听到了风声
Somehow,Murdoch had got wind of it in jail,
并且让艾伯特知道他非常恼怒
and let Albert know he was furious.
我曾希望牢狱之苦能让他找回理智
I'd hoped prison had brought him to his senses,
但当我发现他依旧沉迷后
but when I realised he was just as obsessed,
我就去店里取走了它
I went to the shop and took it.
期望他能停止他的疯狂行为
I hoped to put a stop to his madness,
他却拿艾伯特出气
but he took it out on Albert.
拿着吧
Take it.
毁了它 或者把它交给警察
Get rid of it or give it to the police.
默多克会想尽一起办法得到它
Murdoch will do anything to get his hands on it.
我们该走了
We should go.
你说它有神奇的法力嘛?
You think it has special powers?
我想你最好不要碰它 简
I don't think you should touch that,Jane.
哦 你起得很早 小姐
Oh,you're up early,Miss.
我恐怕早餐还没准备好
I'm afraid breakfast isn't quite ready.
没关系 巴特勒先生
That's alright,Mr Butler.
我得去罗德教授那里 把这个戒指拿给他鉴定
I need to get to Professor Rhodes and have this ring authenticated.
早上好 两位 希望你们今天没有什么计划
'Morning,you two. Hope you don't have any big plans for today.
怎么? 需要我们做什么?
Why? What have you got for us?
也没什么 我想让你们待在这里
Nothing. I want you to stay here.
把所有的门窗锁好 前门后门也别放过
Lock all the doors and windows,the rear and front gates.
在我回来之前 不许任何人离开
No-one is to leave this house until I return,
特别是简
especially not Jane.
真漂亮 可惜我只在书中看过对它的描述
It's beautiful. I've only seen depictions of it,of course.
这枚戒指曾经待在曼塞斯法老的手上?
So this would have been on King Memses's finger?
极有可能 椭圆图案中间就是他的王室名号
More than likely. This cartouche encloses his throne name.
福尔曾想带队回到卢克索找回那具木乃伊
Foyle wanted to bring a team back to Luxor to retrieve the mummy.
当然 没能成功
Never happened,of course.
那这个戒指有什么重要意义?
So what's the significance of the ring?
埃及人相信 如果在戒指上刻上你的名字
Well,Egyptians believed if your name was written down,
它就会认你为主
it identified you
确保你死后来生还能继续为王
and assured your ascendance to the afterlife.
- 然后四名女神就会保护你? - 没错
- And the four goddesses protected you? - Yes.
是的 大多数石棺的四角都有
Yes,most sarcophagi have the four goddesses
女神的翅膀交叉环绕
wrapping their wings around each corner
以求在黄泉上保护灵魂
to protect the soul on its journey.
我也帮你破译好了
And I have those translations for you.
只是一些标记 短语罢了
They're just notes,phrases.
第一个的意思是'祭献'
The first one means 'to dedicate'.
而对于第二个碎块
And the simplest translation
最简单的解释就是 '女童'
of the second deben is 'the girl child'.
祭献女童
To dedicate the girl child.
这就是他一直要做的事情
So that's what he thinks he's been doing.
女童 也可以说是女儿
Girl child,or possibly daughter.
能不能借用一下你的电话?
Would you mind if I use your telephone?
请便
Please.
应该有人在才对啊
There should be somebody there.
人都跑到哪儿去了?
Where the hell is everybody?
替我向费雪小姐问好
Give Miss Fisher my regards.
巴特勒先生! 伯特!
Mr Butler! Bert!
伯特! 醒醒 快醒醒!
Bert! Wake up! Wake up!
噢 桃乐西 不
Oh,Dot. No.
简
Jane.
简?
Jane?
简去哪儿了?
Where's Jane?
我要更多车在外巡逻 那个男人疯了
I want more cars out there. The man's a lunatic.
不计任何代价也要阻止他
I don't care what you have to do to stop him.
他用在艾伯特 蒙克顿和沃特斯上的
Whatever he used on Albert Monkton and Waters,
肯定是同一种药
it must've been the same drug.
它能在五分钟之内让人全身麻痹
It completely paralyses within five minutes!
- 你认为牛奶有问题? - 肯定是!
- You said it was the milk? - It must've been!
他肯定是
He must have tampered with the bottles
今早牛奶送达后做了手脚
after they were delivered this morning.
好吧 我们冷静地分析一下
Alright. Let's go through the facts calmly.
你叫我怎么冷静
How can I be calm when the fact is,
我压根不知道福尔可能带她去哪?!
we haven't the faintest idea where Foyle's taken her!
探长 我刚接到悲伤女士教堂的电话
Inspector. I've just had a call from Our Lady of Sorrows.
我的主啊 谁会做出这种事来?
Dear Lord,who could have done such a thing?
他对她做了什么? 他又打算对简怎样?
What has he done to her? And what are his plans for Jane?
哦 杰克
Oh,Jack.
这些是包括蜜儿特和詹妮在内
These are all the girls,including Myrtle and Janey,
在福尔执教的三年内
who disappeared in the area around the university
在大学附近失踪的所有女孩
over the three years Foyle was teaching there.
四名女神
The four goddesses.
福尔认为他需要四个女神
Foyle believed he needed four goddesses
在他通往来生的路上保护他
to protect his journey to the afterlife.
我在努力找出她们之间的共同点
I'm struggling to make any similarities.
她们并没什么相似的地方 年龄各异
Their paths never crossed,their ages varied,
社会阶层不一样 环境也不同
different social classes,different circumstances.
生日 为什么写在这里?
Birthday. Why is this written here?
他告诉蜜儿特说 他女儿的生日跟她的相近
He told Myrtle his daughter's birthday was close to hers.
但是 他压根并没有女儿
Of course he doesn't have a daughter.
但福尔自己的生日跟曼塞斯法老是同一天
But Foyle's own birthday was the same day as King Memses,
是埃及古历的冬月二十一号 究竟是哪天?
the 21st day of Proyet. What is that?
默多克的生日是1880年12月21日
Murdoch's date of birth was the 21 December 1880.
那其他女孩的生日呢?
What about these other girls?
她们的生日是什么时候?
What are their birthdates?
琼・罗森 1904年12月21日
Joan Rosen,21 December 1904.
德瑞儿・凯利 1903年12月21日
Deidre Kelly,21 December 1903.
艾瑞斯・富尔顿 1901年12月21日
Iris Fulton,21 December 1901.
如果再加上你妹妹 他就凑齐他的四个女神了
If you add your sister's name,he already has his four goddesses.
但我妹妹的生日不是12月21 是9月21
But my sister's birthday wasn't 21 December. It was 21 September.
什么? 我以为...
What? I thought...
我爸爸在登记詹妮的生日那天喝多了
My father was drunk when he registered Janey's birth,
就在出生证上面写错了日期
and he put the wrong date on the certificate.
福尔带走的应该是我 不是詹妮
It should have been me Foyle took instead of Janey.
十二月是我的生日 杰克
It's my birthday,Jack.
仲夏夜前夕 跟其他女孩一样
Midsummer's Eve,same as the others.
我才是福尔的第四个女神
I'm Foyle's fourth goddess.
这就是他纠缠我的原因
That's why he's after me.
所以要确保他来生地位
So all he needs now for his ascension into the afterlife
- 还需要你 - 还有那枚戒指
- is you. - And the ring.
- 什么戒指? - 一个马蹄型的银戒指
- What ring? - A silver stirrup ring.
属于曼塞斯法老的戒指
It belonged to King Memses.
不过特里萨・卡瓦莉把它给了我
But Teresa Cavalli gave it to me.
还有证据?
More evidence?
我把它拿给大学的罗德教授了
I took it to Prof Rhodes at the university.
福尔可以得到我 只要他放了简
Foyle can have me,if he lets Jane go.
你不能去自投罗网啊
You can't go and offer yourself.
罗德是福尔名单上的最后一个
Rhodes is the last one on Foyle's list,
而他又有戒指 我得回去找他
and he has the ring. I need to go back there.
我不会让你去的
I won't let you.
- 你被捕了 - 什么?
- You're under arrest. - What?
- 为了保证你的安全 - 别说傻话了
- For your own safety. - Don't be absurd.
你根本没权利拘留我
You have no grounds for holding me.
啊! 这就是理由!
Hmm! That's it!
你被正式指控袭击警员
You're officially charged with assaulting a police officer,
以及隐瞒证据
and withholding evidence.
警探 没收费雪小姐手包里的枪
Constable,remove Miss Fisher's gun from her handbag,
再把她送去牢里
and escort her to the lock up.
对不住了 小姐
I'm sorry,Miss.
对不住了 小姐 对不住..
I'm sorry,Miss. I'm sorry,Miss...
你不能这么做!
You can't do this!
- 这都是我的错 - 不 小姐 别这么说
- This is all my fault. - No,Miss. Don't say that.
赛斯跟伯特都在想办法 警察也在搜寻
Cec and Bert are doing what they can and the police are looking.
请你务必吃点东西吧
Please just try to eat something.
我失去了詹妮 现在又要失去简
I failed Janey and now I've failed Jane.
- 不会的 - 那可怜的孩子该会多害怕啊
- No. Can you imagine how terrified that poor child must be?
而我却被困在这个可恶的牢房里!
And I'm stuck in this wretched cell!
如果福尔抓到你 简也不会好受的
But it won't help Jane if Foyle gets his hands on you too.
他肯定得去找罗德
He has to go after Rhodes at some point.
只要守株待兔就行了
It's just a matter of waiting for him.
- 除非... - 什么?
- Unless... - What?
有人在福尔坐牢的时候
Somebody told Foyle about that stirrup ring
把戒指的事情告诉了他
when he was in prison.
还有谁知道这件事?
Who else would know?
罗德 这就是为何他是死亡名单的最后一个
Rhodes. That's why he's last on the list to be killed.
你必须让休把我放出去 桃乐西!
You have to get Hugh to let me out of here,Dot!
杰克有危险!
Jack's in danger!
要喝点茶吗 休? 费雪小姐不肯喝
Would you like some tea,Hugh? Miss Fisher won't drink it.
多谢了 桃乐西
Thanks,Dottie.
- 桃乐西! - 你愿为我做任何事吗?
- Dottie! - Would you do anything for me?
- 应该吧 - 那你会不会放芙莱妮小姐走
- Almost. - Would you let Miss Phryne go?
不行 关她是为她的安全着想
No,because she's locked up for her own good,
而且如果放她走 我会丢了我的工作 桃乐西
and if I let her out,I'll lose my job,Dottie.
别...别动
Don't... don't move.
- 你不会开枪打我的 - 我也不想 休
- You wouldn't shoot me. - I wouldn't want to,Hugh.
但如果这样能帮芙莱妮小姐 还能救简
but if it means helping Miss Phryne go and save Jane's life,
那么...好吧 我必须开枪打你的腿
then... well,I'll have to shoot you in the leg.
我说真的 休!
I mean it,Hugh!
我从十二岁起就开始打兔子了
I've been shooting rabbits since I was 12.
不 你没有 桃乐西
No,you haven't,Dottie.
桃乐西
Dot.
别哭啊 拜托 桃乐西
Don't cry. Please,Dottie,
做什么事都行 就是别哭啊
anything but that. Don't cry.
只是...
It's just...
芙莱妮小姐要我帮忙
Miss Phryne wants me to help,
探长又有危险 简又...
and the Inspector is in danger,and Jane...
豁出去了 拿枪指着我
Come on,then. Point the gun at me.
拿枪指...
Point the...
嘿! - 抱歉了 休
Hey! - Sorry,Hugh,
但是杰克或许会因我而身陷险境
but Jack may be in danger because of me.
- 那带我一起去 - 我也想
- Take me with you then. - I'd love to.
但在我搞清情况之前
But until I know what I'm up against,
我不想兴师动众
I'd rather not make a grand entrance.
小姐!小姐 别...求你啦!
Miss! Miss,don't... please!
要先发制人哦
Just need a head start.
罗德教授吗? 我是杰克・罗宾逊探长
Professor Rhodes? I'm Detective Inspector Jack Robinson.
- 探长 请进 - 谢谢
- Inspector. Come in. - Thank you.
我听说了蒙克顿先生跟沃特斯先生的事
I heard about Mr Monkton and Mr Waters.
真是噩耗
Terrible news.
今天早些时候 我们发现了卡瓦莉小姐的尸体
And Miss Cavalli's body was found earlier today.
她是被勒死的
She was strangled.
哦 不 我还一直希望她躲得远远的呢
Oh. No. I'd hoped she was somewhere safe from him.
她有一个福尔想要的戒指
She had a ring that Foyle was after.
我想费雪小姐把它留在了你这里
I believe Miss Fisher left it with you.
没错 是第五王朝的罕见珍宝
Yes. A rare artefact from the Fifth Dynasty.
是曼塞斯法老统治的时期
The reign of King Memses.
考虑到这是我们调查的一部分
Given it's part of our investigation,
我们要把它拿到警察局保管
we'll have to take it into police custody.
是的 当然
Yes,of course.
费雪小姐离开的很匆忙 但我把戒指连同
Miss Fisher left in a hurry,but I kept it safe for her,
她带来的其他古董一起妥善保管了
with the rest of the antiquities collection.
在楼下放着
Downstairs.
在这
Here.
这些也是从曼塞斯国王坟墓中挖到的
These are from King Memses' tomb as well.
都是宗教仪式用的
They were ceremonial.
上面的雕刻描述了仲夏日前夕
The engravings tell the story of Memses' ascension
- 曼塞斯升天的故事 - 令人难忘啊
- on Midsummer's Eve. - Impressive.
它们是我个人收藏的一部分
They're part of my personal collection,
但我最终会把它们全部赠与博物馆
but I'll bequeath them to the museum eventually.
教授 那戒指在哪?
So where's the ring,Professor?
把他跟女孩放一块儿
Put him with the girl.
剩下的就是等了
Now we wait.
简!
Jane!
简 能听见我说话吗?
Jane,can you hear me?
我是罗宾逊探长 嘘
It's Inspector Robinson. Shh,shh.
干得好 芙莱妮・费雪
Well done,Phryne Fisher.
喜欢追踪我留下的踪迹么?
Did you like my trail of crumbs?
你可以现在就杀了我
You can kill me now,
但你就要和女儿和那位警官永别了
but you'll never see your daughter or policeman alive.
我的第四位女神
My fourth goddess.
如果你欣然地接受
Your glorious destiny.
那便是你光辉的命运
If you choose to accept it willingly.
我曾愿牺牲自己换我妹妹一命
I would've willingly given my life for my sister's.
现在我也愿意牺牲自己 换那两人的名
And now I willingly offer it for the sake of two others,
只要你让他们毫发无损地离开
if you let them go unharmed.
罗德 你怎么能帮这样的人?
How can you help this man,Rhodes?
你对上古世界的着迷
Surely your fascination with the ancient world
怎能让你放纵一个谋害无辜少女的凶手?
cannot overlook the murder of innocent girls?
你如何找到我们四人的?
So how did you find us all?
和你一样夏至时出生
Born on the summer solstice,same as you.
我之前的学生詹姆斯・沃特斯曾在登记处工作
My former student,James Waters,was a registry clerk
记录出生死亡与婚姻
at Births,Deaths and Marriages,
我通过他找到你们所有人
and he led me to you all.
- 你为什么又杀了他 - 因为他背叛了我
- So why did you kill him? - Well,he betrayed me.
就像艾伯特和特里萨 他们...
Like Albert and Teresa. They...
他们都想从我这偷走珍贵的东西
They all tried to steal something precious from me.
这不怪我 费雪小姐 他们迷失了方向
I'm not one to blame,Miss Fisher. They lost their way.
来世他们会有机会再次对我尽忠
They will serve me faithfully again,in the afterlife.
是时候准备我的旅程了
It's time for me to prepare for my journey.
嘘
Sh.
我能理解 你想要被授予
I can understand you wanting the glory
发现曼塞斯国王坟墓的荣誉
of your discovery of King Memses' tomb.
福尔离开后 金杯自然是你的
The golden cups will be rightfully yours after Foyle's gone.
当他因诱拐少女受审判时
I knew Teresa had her fears
我知道特里萨很害怕
when he stood trial for that abduction,
但我没想到他是个杀手
but I didn't think he was a killer.
现在呢? 你的三个老朋友死了之后呢?
And now? After three of your old friends have died?
我无法阻止他
I couldn't do anything to stop it.
艾伯特和沃特斯出事前我完全不知情
I had no warning with Albert and Waters.
那特里萨・卡瓦莉呢?
What about Teresa Cavalli?
如果你告诉我他在哪 你可以救她一命
You could have prevented her death if you'd told me where he was.
是的
Yes.
但你也听见他说的了
But you heard him.
一切都要结束了 他准备杀了自己
This'll all be over soon. He plans to kill himself.
还要让我陪葬
And take me with him.
这次你可是共犯
This time you're an accomplice.
除非你亲手杀了罗宾逊探长
Unless you're planning on killing Inspector Robinson yourself,
否则他肯定会尽全力判你绞刑
he'll make sure you hang for it.
没用
It's no use.
锁弄不坏 这门也很重
I can't break the lock and the door weighs a ton.
我需要件东西撬开它
I need something to pry it open with.
木乃伊行不?
What about the mummy?
法老在下葬时
Pharaohs were sometimes buried
常常带些小的护身符和珠宝
with little amulets and jewellery.
或许能在布带找到些有用的
Maybe we could find something in the wrappings.
好主意 简
Good thinking,Jane.
啊
Aah.
当我们喝下圣杯之水时
When we drink from these sacred cups,
你我将会安静而坦然地离开尘世
you and I will leave this mortal life in peace and full knowledge.
费雪小姐 你先来
First you,Miss Fisher.
你的四肢会变得沉重 但你的心灵会无比平静
Your limbs will grow heavy but your mind will calm.
我会尽我所能 很快让你
And I will help you cross over to the other side
去到另一个世界
as swiftly as I can.
我妹妹死的时候受折磨了么?
Did my sister die in pain?
没有 一秒都没有 她...
No. Not for a moment,no. She...
她死得很光荣
She died gloriously.
没有痛苦和恐惧
Without pain or fear.
我非常小心的扶她躺下休息了
And I laid her to rest with great care.
- 她在哪? - 和其他人在一起
- Where is she? - With the others.
我把她的灵魂埋在了芦苇地里
I buried her soul in the Field of Reeds.
我把她们都埋在了小河上游的
I buried them all in the grove of weeping willows
柳树林里 每个地方都按顺序标记好了
at the head of the river,each place marked in order.
你会躺在你妹妹身边 直到永远
And you too will lie beside your sister,for all time.
这是生育和魔法女神艾西斯的标志
It's the symbol of Isis,Goddess of fertility and magic,
保护孩子和亡者
protector of children and the dead.
听上去不错
Sounds perfect.
我怎么确保你会放他们走?
How do I know you'll let them go?
我死后 放了杰克和简
Jack and Jane,after I'm gone?
我会放了他们
I'll release them.
在我跟着你们奔赴来生之前
Before I follow you both to the afterlife.
不 我不相信他
No,I don't trust him.
我相信你的话 而不相信他的
I believe your word but not his.
- 他不是你忠实的仆人 - 让她喝
- He isn't your loyal servant. - Make her drink.
快喝 要不我立马杀了你
Drink it or I'll shoot you now.
全喝光!
All of it!
但我说的都是真话 罗德不是你虔诚的信徒
But I meant what I said. Rhodes is not one of your faithful.
他不会随你到来生或任何其他地方...
He won't follow you to the afterlife or anywhere else...
闭嘴! - 他一直等着
Quiet! - He's waiting you out
是为了霸占那些珍宝
for the sake of the treasure.
他会宣布是他发现的法老坟墓 然后独享荣耀
He'll claim the discovery of King Memses' tomb for his own glory.
- 把枪给我 - 这是一派胡言
- Give me the gun. - None of it's true.
我知道 因为计划原本就是
I know,because the plan was always
为表明忠心 你要先我一步去往来世
that you would precede me to the afterlife for your own loyalty.
- 把枪给我 - 不
- Give me the gun. - No.
不!
No!
啊!
Aah!
在这等着
Wait here.
芙莱妮!
Phryne!
但...你是自愿来的!
B-but... but you came willingly!
我来是为查出我妹妹的真相
I came willingly to find out what happened to my sister.
是为了营救简和杰克
And to rescue Jane and Jack.
不是为你而来
I didn't come for you.
- 我只想引领你们 - 你把路引向了地狱
- I only tried to lead the way. - You led the way to hell.
- 求你了! - 不
- Please! - No.
你不会得到永生的
You're not headed for eternal life.
你会回到监狱等待绞刑
You're going back to jail so you can hang.
哦 简
Oh,Jane.
- 对不起 - 芙莱妮
- I'm so sorry. - Phryne.
如果你所记得的的确是这样...
So if that's a true statement of events as you recall them...
普璐登斯姑妈已经安排好
Aunt Prudence has organised
要把我妹妹葬在家族的墓地里
for my sister to be buried in the family plot.
詹妮因我而死
Janey died instead of me.
所以你欠她一条命 你要好好活下去
So you owe it to her to keep living to the hilt.
别让我注意到你浪费生命
Not that I noticed you wasting a moment.
打搅了
Excuse me.
他们在找你 小姐
They're asking for you,Miss.
我的生日聚会
My birthday party.
夏至
Summer solstice.
来为我庆祝吧
Help me to celebrate.
再多来点香槟 巴特勒先生!
More champagne,Mr B!